罗德里·费恩爵士改编好了管弦乐曲
Orchestrations were arranged by Sir Rhodri Fanning
叶夫林·布利斯女爵士 是林恩国王乐队的演奏者之一
and Dame Evelyn Blish is a member of the Kings Lynn players.
欢迎下周再次收看
So tune in again next week
更多“新闻在线”的节目
for more from the What's My Line team.
今天的节目到此为止了
And that brings us to the end of programming for today.
亚历山德拉皇宫电视台每位成员
So, from all of us here at Alexandra Palace,
祝大家有个美好的晚上
a very good night.
透支200英镑
£200 overdrawn.
只有奇迹能救我了
I need a miracle.
他真逗 他每次都能让我发笑
He's a caution, that one. He does make me laugh.
噢 我们的主人回来了
Oh, our lord and master.
瑞塔 我下班了
Rita, I'm off out.
爸爸
Dad.
我跟你说了多少次了 儿子
Oh, how many times, son?
看情况
We'll see.
但每家都有电视机 爸爸
But everyone's getting a telly, Dad,
甚至加里格先生
even Mr Gallagher.
67号的贝尔斯一家
And the Bells at number 67.
或许为了加冕礼买一台
Well, perhaps we'll get one for the Coronation.
如果你幸运的话
If you're lucky.
看情况
We'll see.
别等着了
Don't wait up.
我听说电视会腐蚀大脑
I heard they rot your brains.
把大脑变成浆糊
Rot them into soup
然后脑浆会从你耳朵里流出来
and your brain comes pouring out of your ears.
都是电视干的
That's what television does.
麦吉派先生
Mr. Magpie?
哦 能听见我吗 麦吉派
Oh Mr Magpie? Whoo-hoo! Can you hear me, Magpie?
听见了
Yes.
我一定在做梦
I must be dreaming.
不 这不是梦
Oh, no. This isn't a dream.
那我一定是疯了
I'm going doolally, then.
根本没有 亲爱的
Not at all, sweetheart.
现在 你坐好了吗
Now, are you sitting comfortably?
很好
Good
那我们开始吧
then we'll begin.
我以为我们要去维加斯时代
I thought we'd be going for the Vegas era.
你知道的 白色喇叭裤 爆炸头
You know, the white flares and the chest hair.
你在开玩笑吧
You are kidding, aren't you?
如果你想见猫王 就去50年代后期
If you wanna see Elvis, you go for the late '50s.
在汉堡出现之前
The time before burgers!
人们叫他佩维斯 他那时还有腰的哦
When they called him "The Pelvis" and he still had a waist!
更重要的是 你看他很时髦
What's more, you see him in style!
跟我上路吧 姑娘
You going my way, doll?
还有别的地方可去吗 花花公子
Is there any other way to go, daddy-o?
就是这么回事 帅哥
Straight from the fridge, man!
你行话说的挺溜啊
Hey! you speak the lingo!
是啊…这个嘛
Yeah, well,
我和妈妈常看克里夫·理查德的电影
me and Mum, Cliff Richard movies
每周一的银行休息日
every Bank Holiday Monday.
克里夫
Cliff!
我就 知道你妈妈会是克里夫的影迷
I knew your mother would be a Cliff fan.
我们要去哪里
Where we off to?
艾德·苏利文 电视制片场
Ed Sullivan TV studios.
猫王在节目上演奏了《猎犬》 引发热议
Elvis did Hound Dog on one of the shows. There were loads of complaints.
幸运的话 我们能赶上
Bit of luck, we'll just catch it.
那个电视制片场应该在…
And that would be the TV studios in, what,
纽约
New York?
没错
That's the one!
融入纽约的氛围
Digging that New York vibe!
这里也许还是纽约
Well, this could still be New York.
我是说 这看上去很像纽约
I mean, this looks very New York to me.
一种…伦敦风的纽约 但…
London-y New York, mind, but...
挂那些旗子干什么
What are all the flags for?
好极了
Smashing!
好极了 是吧
Smashing, innit?
活灵活现 就像身临其境一样
You'd have thought they was in the room with ya, eh?
很好吧 汤米 你说得没错
Fair do's, Tommy, you had a point.
新电视
New television.
看 这下你们高兴了吧 瑞塔
There, that should cheer you up a bit, Rita?
给我们笑一笑
Give us a smile, then, eh?
我不能
I can't.
现在事情不一样了 因为她…
Nothing's the same anymore. Not with her...
别再说这个了
Stop going on about it!
但她的脸 艾迪
But her face, Eddie.
她怎么了
What happened to her?
那可怕的脸
That awful face.
别说了
I said stop it!
她醒了
She's awake.
我想她饿了
I think she's hungry.
去吧 先生
There you go, sir.
都为那件重大事件接好了
All wired up for the great occasion.
重大事件
Great occasion?
你指的是什么
What do you mean?
你住哪儿的 殖民地吗
Where you been living, out in the colonies?
当然是加冕礼
The Coronation of course!
是什么加冕礼
And what Coronation's that, then?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
那个加冕礼
The Coronation!
女王的加冕礼
It's the Queen's!
伊丽莎白女王
Queen Elizabeth!
噢 这是1953年
Oh! Is this 1953?
上一次检查还是的
Last time I looked.
是时候搞一次大排场 我们最擅长了
Time for a lovely bit of pomp and circumstance. What we do best.
看看这些电视天线
Look at all the TV aerials.
似乎每家都有一台
Looks like everyone's got one.
太奇怪了 我外婆说那时电视很稀有
That's weird. My mum said tellies were so rare,
大家都得挤到一个房子里看
they all had to pile into one house.
这里不一样 亲爱的
Not round here, love.
麦吉派的绝妙电视
Magpie's Marvellous Tellies.
只要五镑一台
Only five quid a pop!
这真是辉煌的一年
Oh, but this is a brilliant year,
经典
classic!
发明彩色印刷
Technicolor!
征服世界最高峰
Everest climbed!
一切不再定量供给
Everything off the ration!
一个摆脱了战争阴影的国家
A nation throwing off the shackles of war
正朝着更快乐 更美好的未来发展
and looking forward to a happier, brighter future!
谁来帮帮我 泰德
Someone help me, please! Ted!
放开他 他是我丈夫
Leave him alone! That's my husband!
请不要
Please!
怎么了
What's going on?
你在做什么
Oi! What are you doing?
警察办事 别挡道 先生
Police business. Get out of the way, sir.
他们带走了谁
Who did they take?
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
一定是加里格先生
Must be Mr Gallagher.
这种事到处都在发生
It's happening all over the place.
他们变成了怪物
They're turning into monsters.
汤米
Tommy!
别多嘴
Not one word.
进来 马上
Get inside now!
对不起 我最好按他说的做
Sorry, I'd better do as he says.
上车
All aboard!
执行"货棚"计划 行动
Operation Market Stall. Go! Go! Go!
跟丢了
Lost them.
他们是怎样甩掉我们的
How did they get away from us?
他们竟然没回来
I'm surprised they didn't turn back
以卤莽驾驶而逮捕你
and arrest you for reckless driving.
你驾照考试过了吗
Have you actually passed your test?
黑衣男子
Men in black?
消失的警车
Vanishing police cars?
这是丘吉尔时代的英国
This is Churchill's England,
不是斯大林时代的苏联
not Stalin's Russia.
那个男孩说 怪物
Monsters, that boy said.
也许我们应该问问邻居
Maybe we should go and ask the neighbours.
这就是我喜欢你的一点
That's what I like about you,
接地气
the domestic approach.
谢谢
Thank you.
等等 这是夸还是贬
Hold on. Was that an insult?
我已经完成了
MAGPIE: I've finished it
按照你的指示
as you instructed.
你做得非常好 麦吉派先生
That's awfully good of you, Mr Magpie.
那你会快点离开吗
So you'll go soon?
放过我
You'll leave me?
看情况
We'll see
如果你表现好的话
If you're a very good boy.
求你了
Please.
你令我灼痛
You're burning me.
这里面
Inside.
我的眼睛后面 很痛
Behind my eyes. It hurts.
甚至我的记忆也受损了
Even my memories hurt.
我只希望事情变回过去的样子
I just want things back like they used to be.
但你这个世界总是忙来忙去
Oh, but this world of yours is busy, busy, busy,
向前迈进新纪元吧
forging ahead into a brand-new age.
你再也不能回头
You can never go back.
这是你们的悲剧
That's your tragedy.
但是现在
But now
时机差不多成熟了 麦吉派
the time is almost ripe, Magpie.
重要时刻
Cometh the hour,
重要之人
cometh the man.
或重要女人
Or lady.
外婆
Gran?
外婆 是我 我是汤米
Gran, it's me. It's Tommy.
我要进来了 外婆
I'm gonna come in, Gran.
往后站
Stand back.
不要…
just don't...
对不起 但我得进来
I'm sorry, but I've got to come in.
你以为你在做什么
What do you think you're doing?
我们得想办法帮她 爸爸
We gotta try and help her, Dad.
给我钥匙
Give me that key.
我说 给我钥匙 现在
I said give me that key right now.
别以为这事就这么完了
And don't think I've finished with you.
我警告你多少次了 每一次
All the warnings I've given you and every time,
每一次 你都不听我的话
every time, you disobey me.
我们不能就这样把她锁起来
We can't just lock her away.
抱歉 小伙子 我在说话
Excuse me, sunshine, I am talking.
你就别想上大学了
And you can forget that college nonsense.
你要和我一起工作
You're gonna come and work alongside me.
动动你的懒骨头
Get your hands dirty for once.
天哪 她什么时候才会停
Oh, Lord! Won't she ever stop?
没事的 瑞塔 我的甜心
There, there, Rita, my sweet.
一切照常
Business as usual.
现在 我们把这些挂满整个屋子
Now, let's get these up all over the house
庆祝陛下
in honour of Her Majesty.
但艾迪
But, Eddie,
如果她快死了呢
what if she's dying?
我在说话
I am talking!
好多了
That's better.
清静点了
A little bit of hush.
嗨
Hi! Hi!
你们是谁
Who are you, then?
让我们看看 通过你的外表
Let's see, judging by the look of you,
居家男人 漂亮的房子 参过军
family man, nice house, decent wage, fought in the war,
因此我代表女王和这个国家
therefore, I represent Queen and country!
在女王加冕日到来之前
just doing a check of her forthcoming
我来检查一下国民做的准备
Majesty's subjects before the great day.
不介意我们进来吧 我猜不介意 谢谢
Don't mind if we come in? No, I didn't think you did. Thank you.
不错 很好
Not bad, very nice,
保持的很好 恭喜你 太太…
very well kept. I'd like to congratulate you, Mrs...?
康诺利  瑞塔 我能处理
Connolly. Now then, Rita. I can handle this.
这位先生是个大人物
This gentleman's a proper representative.
别管我的妻子 她老喋喋不休
Don't mind the wife. She rattles on a bit.
或许她应该多说一点
Well, maybe she should rattle on a bit more.
我不确定你尽了爱国职责
I'm not convinced you're doing your patriotic duty.
那些旗帜
Those flags,
为什么不把它们挂起来
why are they not flying?
快点 瑞塔 我告诉过你
There we are, Rita, I told you.
把他们挂起来 女王和国家
Get them up. Queen and country.
对不起
I'm sorry.
去做 现在去做
Get it done. Do it now.
等等
Hold on a minute.
照这位先生说的做  等等
Like the gentleman says... Hold on a minute.
你也有手 康诺利先生
You've got hands, Mr Connolly.
两只大手
Two big hands.
那为什么让你妻子去做
Then why is that your wife's job?
这是家务 不是吗
Well, it's housework, innit?
所以就是女人的工作吗
And that's a woman's job?
当然是
Course it is.
康诺利先生 女王的性别是
Mr Connolly, what gender is the Queen?
她是女性
She's a female.
那你是说女王应该家务了
And are you suggesting the Queen does the housework?
不 没有的事
No, not at all.
那就去忙吧
Then get busy!
好的 先生
Right. Yes, sir.
你会为我们感到自豪的
You'll be proud of us, sir!
我们会把英国旗挂满左边 右边和中间
We'll have Union Jacks left, right and center!
对不起 康诺利先生 等一等
Excuse me, Mr Connolly. Hang on a minute.
你说"Union Jacks"
Union Jacks?
对啊 不是吗
Yes, that's right, isn't it?
你应该说"Union Flag"
That's the Union Flag.
只有飘扬在海上时才能叫"Union Jack"
It's the Union jack only when it's flown at sea.
对不起 我道歉
Oh, I'm sorry. I do apologise.
别再犯这样的错误 这就对了 马上干活
Well, don't get it wrong again. There's a good man. Now get to it!
好了 漂亮又舒服
Right, then, nice and comfy.
陛下的闲暇时光
At her Majesty's leisure!
英国旗
Union Flag?
妈妈和一个水手约会过
Mum went out with a sailor.
我猜也是
I bet she did.
对了 我是博士 这是洛斯
Anyway, I'm the Doctor and this is Rose.
你们是
And you are?
汤米
Tommy.
过来这里坐 汤米
Well, sit yourself down, Tommy.
看看这个
Have a look at this.
我喜欢电视 你呢
I love telly, don't you?
是 我觉得很棒
Yeah, I think it's brilliant.
好家伙
Good man.
继续工作 康先生…
Keep working, Mr C !
现在 何不跟我说说发生什么了
Now, why don't you tell me what's wrong?
你刚说你是医生吗
Did you say you were a doctor?
是的 我是
Yes, I am.
你能帮帮她吗
Can you help her?
求你了
Oh, please.
你能帮帮她吗 医生
Can you help her, Doctor?
瑞塔 我不认为这位先生有必要知道…
Now then, Rita, I don't think the gentleman needs to know.
这位先生需要知道
Oh, the gentleman does.
告诉我们发生什么了 我们能帮忙
Tell us what's wrong, and we can help.
没事
It's all right.
没事 来这儿
It's all right. Come here.
噢 没事
Oh, It's all right.
等一下
Hold on a minute.
女王和国家是一回事 但这里是我家
Queen and Country's one thing, but this is my house.
我这…我究竟在做什么
What the... What the hell am I doing?
你给我听着 医生
Now you listen here, Doctor.
你也许有一些奇奇怪怪的特权
You may have fancy qualifications,
但我屋子下发生的事是我的家事
but what goes on under my roof is my business.
人们是不是都被…
Not if people are being bundled into...
我在说话
I am talking!
我没有在听
And I'm not listening!
现在 康诺利先生
Now you, Mr Connolly,
如果你不让我帮助的话
you are staring into a deep,
你将面对一个又深又黑的麻烦深渊
dark pit of trouble if you don't let me help.
所以我命令你 先生
So I'm ordering you, sir,
告诉我怎么回事
tell me what's going on!
她不肯停下来
She won't stop.
她一直不停下
She never stops.
我们开始听到些流言
We started hearing stories,
各个地方都有
all round the place.
那些…改变的人
People who have changed.
各家庭都保密 他们都吓坏了
Families keeping it secret 'cause they were scared.
然后警察开始调查
Then the police started finding out.
我们不知道原因 没人知道
We don't know how, no one does.
他们突然出现
They just turn up.
走进屋里把人带走
They come to the door and take them.
不分昼夜
Any time of the day or night.
给我看看
Show me.
外婆
Gran,
我是汤米
it's Tommy.
没事的 外婆 我带人来帮忙了
It's all right, Gran. I've brought help.
她的脸完全消失了
Her face has completely gone.
几乎没有电击过的痕迹
Scarcely an electrical impulse left.
基本上关闭了神经系统 只剩下空壳
Almost complete neural shutdown. It's just ticking over.
就像她的大脑被…
It's like her brain's been
清空了
wiped clean.
我们怎么办 医生
What are we gonna do, Doctor?
我们甚至不能喂她
We can't even feed her.
有人来了
We've got company!
他们是来抓她的
It's them. They've come for her!
这个发生之前 她在哪里 做了什么
What was she doing before this happened? Where was she?
快告诉我 想想
Tell me, quickly, think!
我无法思考了
I can't think.
她没离开房子 只是…
She doesn't leave the house. She was just...
等等 我有三个很重要 很高深
Hold on a minute! There are three important, brilliant
且复杂的理由说明你应该听我的
and complicated reasons why you should listen to me.
第一…
One...
博士
Doctor!
放开她 你们会伤到她的
Leave her alone. You'll hurt her!
妈妈
Mum!
博士 不要伤害她
Come back. Don't hurt her.
瑞塔 进去
Back inside, Rita.
她是我妈妈
She's my mother!
我说 马上进去
Back inside now, I said!
好一记右勾拳
Hell of a right hook.
必须小心着点那个
Have to watch out for that.
算了 进去
Don't fight it. Back inside.
洛斯 过来
Rose, come on!
回里面去
Get back inside.
他们带走她了
But they took her.
洛斯 我们又要跟丢了
Rose! We're gonna lose them again!
他们带走她了 那是外婆 他们把她带走了
But they took her! That was Gran and they took her!
回到里面去
Come on, back inside, lad.
他们是怎么找到她的 谁告密了
How did they find her? Who told them?
你 滚出我的屋子
You! Get the hell out of my house!
我弄好了 走了
I'm going. I'm done.
很高兴见到你们 汤米
Nice to meet you, Tommy.
康诺利女士
Mrs Connolly.
至于你 康诺利先生
And as for you, Mr Connolly,
只有白痴才会把国旗挂反
only an idiot hangs the Union ﬂag upside down.
真丢人
Shame on you.
很不错
Oh, very good.
非常不错
Very good.
待在原地别动
Stay where you are!
对不起 小姐 恐怕你来晚了
I'm sorry, miss. I'm afraid you're too late.
我正准备锁门
I was just about to lock the door.
是吗 我想买台电视
Yeah? Well, I wanna buy a telly.
请明天来吧
Come back tomorrow, please.
你们明天要关门 不是吗
You'll be closed, won't you?
什么
What?
为了大日子
For the big day?
加冕典礼
The Coronation?
是是 当然 大日子
Yes, yes, of course. The big day.
你会找到地方看加冕典礼的
I'm sure you'll find somewhere to watch it.
请走吧
Please go.
据我所知 半个伦敦都有电视了
Seems to me half of London's got a television,
因为你们基本上白送给人们
since you're practically giving them away.
我有我的理由
I have my reasons.
什么理由
And what are they?
饿
Hungry!
那是什么
What's that?
只是电视
It's just the television.
其中一档时髦节目
One of these modern programmes.
我真的觉得你应该离开了
Now, I really do think you should leave
马上
right now.
除非你回答我的问题
Not until you've answered my questions.
为什么你的电视机那么便宜
How comes your televisions are so cheap?
这是我的爱国职责
It's my patriotic duty.
为了让尽可能多的人看到加冕典礼
Seems only right that as many folk as possible get to watch the Coronation.
我们也许正在失去大英帝国 但我们仍会感到自豪
We may be losing the Empire, but we can still be proud!
估计有两千万人会观看
Twenty million people they reckon will be watching.
想像一下
Imagine that.
两千万人不可能出错吧
And 20 million people can't be wrong, eh?
所以 你干嘛不早点回家
So why don't you get yourself back home
为迎接这大日子早起呢
and get up bright and early for the big day?
不 我要查清楚了才离开
No, I'm not leaving till I've seen everything.
我必须关门了
I need to close.
麦吉派先生…
Mr Magpie,
外面有怪事在发生
something's happening out there.
普通人遭到袭击然后改变了
Ordinary people are being struck down and changed
家里唯一的新东西就是电视
and the only new thing in the house is a television.
你的电视
Your television.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我就知道会有这一天
I knew this would happen.
我会被人发现
I knew I'd be found out.
好吧 就你和我
All right, then, just you and me.
你全部交代吧
You gonna come clean, then?
你到底是为了什么
What's really in it for you?
我
For me?
也许是为了一点安宁
Perhaps some peace.
从哪里
From what?
从她那里
From her.
但这只是电视机里的女人
Well, that'sjust a woman on the telly.
只是一栏节目
That's just a programme.
多可爱的小姑娘
What a pretty little girl.
天哪 你在和我说话吗
Oh, my God. Are you talking to me?
是的
Yes.
我在和你说话 小家伙
I'm talking to you, little one.
给了你不合时节的寒颤吧
Unseasonably chilly for the time of year
你觉得呢
don't you think?
你是什么
What are you?
我是电线人
I'm The Wire.
我很饿
And I'm hungry!
麦吉派 帮帮我
Magpie, help me!
想想明天的观众 亲爱的
just think of that audience tomorrow, my dear,
都坐着看加冕礼
all settling down to watch the Coronation.
两千万人
Twenty million people.
一切再也回不到从前了
Things will never be the same again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的对不起
So sorry.
帮帮我
Help me!
晚安 孩子们
Good night, children,
所有地方
everywhere.
从头开始 把你知道的每件事告诉我
Start from the beginning. Tell me everything you know.
首先
Well, for starters,
我知道你用手抓住手肘时指尖不能合拢
I know you can't wrap your hand round your elbow and make your fingers meet.
别和我耍小聪明
Don't get clever with me.
今天在弗罗利泽街见到你 现在又闯入这间设施
You were there today at Florizel Street, and now breaking into this establishment.
你和这事一定有关系
Oh, you're connected with this.
搞清楚自己的处境
Make no mistake.
问题是
Well, the thing is,
毕夏普巡官侦探
Detective Inspector Bishop...
你怎么知道我名字的
How do you know my name?
写在你的领口里的
It's written inside your collar.
祝福你妈妈 但我忍不住这样想
Bless your mum. But I can't help thinking,
巡官侦探
Detective Inspector,
你没真正在做多少侦查工作 是吧
you're not exactly doing much detective-inspecting, are you?
我尽力做我职权范围内的事
I'm doing everything in my power.
你只不过是抓走那些没脸的人并藏起来
All you're doing is grabbing those faceless people and hiding them as fast as you can.
别告诉我这是上头的命令
Don't tell me, orders from above.
加冕典礼大日子 全世界都关注着伦敦
Coronation Day, the eyes of the world are on London Town,
任何问题都要扫出视线之外
so any sort of problem just gets swept out of sight.
国家的形象需要维护
The nation has an image to maintain.
但什么都不做 你不觉得要被逼疯了吗
But doesn't it drive you mad, doing nothing?
你不想出去调查吗
Don't you want to get out there and investigate?
当然想
Course I do.
但是…
But...
尽管众望所归 但我们没有人力
with all the crowds expected, we haven't got the manpower.
即使我们有
Even if we did,
这事超出了我们的见识范围
this is beyond anything we've ever seen.
我不知道该怎么办了
I just don't know anymore.
从军二十年
Twenty years on the force,
我甚至不知道从哪里着手
I don't even know where to start.
我们对发生的事情没有半点头绪
We haven't the faintest clue what's going on.
那…
Well,
情况可以改变
that could change.
怎样
How?
从头开始说
Start from the beginning.
把你知道的一切都告诉我
Tell me everything you know.
一个月前我们开始发现他们
We started finding them about a month ago.
没有无官的人们
Persons left sans visage.
脑袋就这样…一片空白
Heads just...blank
有什么规律吗
Is there any sort of pattern?
从伦敦北部开始蔓延整个城市
It's spreading out from North London, all over the city.
男人 女人 孩子 祖辈
Men, women, kids, grannies.
最有用的线索是 数量极多的案例出现在…
Only real lead is there's been quite a large number in...
弗罗利泽街
Florizel Street.
又发现一个 长官
Found another one, sir.
好样的 克拉提 你看吧 博士
Oh, good man, Crabtree. Here we are, Doctor.
好好看看
Take a good look.
看看能推断出什么
See what you can deduce.
洛斯…
Rose.
你认识她
You know her?
认识她 她是…
Know her? She...
在街上发现她的 倒在大马士革路
They found her in the street apparently, down by Damascus Road.
就这么遗弃了 这不寻常 这是第一个出现在外面的…
just abandoned. That's unusual. That's the first one out in the open...
他们做了什么
They did what?
对不起
I'm sorry?
他们把她留在哪
They left her where?
大街上
just...in the street.
大街上 他们把她留在大街上
In the street. They left her in the street.
他们把她的脸拿走了
They took her face and just chucked her out
然后抛弃到大街上
and left her in the street.
结果让事情变得
And, as a result, that makes things...
简单起来 很简单
simple, very, very simple.
你知道为什么吗
Do you know why?
不
No.
因为现在 毕夏普巡官侦探
Because now, Detective Inspector Bishop,
这个世界上没有力量能够阻止我
there is no power on this Earth that can stop me!
来吧
Come on!
大日子的黎明
The big day dawns.
那个小医生让你高兴的差不多了
You've had your fun with your little Doctor.
但现在你在我这里 瑞塔
But now you're left with me, Rita,
所以你循规蹈矩些
so you'll behave yourself.
笑一笑
And smile.
来吧 大家来吧 吃点东西
Here we go, everyone, here we go!
大家尽情吃 来个三明治
Grub's up. Tuck in, Take a sandwich.
噢 来吧 开始了
Oh, here we go, it's starting.
看看 找个地方 坐下 坐下
Look. Go and take your places. Sit down.
瑞塔 亲爱的 你看看电视机
WOMAN: Rita, love, just look at that telly-box, then!
是不是很神奇 画面好清楚
Innit marvellous? The picture's so clear!
之前我给瑞塔说过 我说
I says to Rita, I says,
“你不用特意去弄头发 亲爱的”
"You didn't need to get your hair done special, love.
“女王是看不见你的”
"The Queen won't be able to see you!"
你的老母亲在哪呢 她不能错过加冕典礼
Where's your old mum, then? She can't go missing it.
对不起 妈妈下不了床
Sorry, Mum can't make it down.
保佑她
Aw, bless her.
也许我们待会儿可以上去看望她
Maybe we could pop up and see her later.
也许可以
Maybe you could.
真是个好主意 是吧 爸爸
It's a good idea. What do you think, Dad?
也许贝蒂姑妈一会能去看看外婆
Maybe Aunty Betty can go and see Gran later.
他很爱他外婆 这小子
Oh, he loves his Gran, this one.
整天围着妈妈转
Proper little mummy's boy all round.
你知道别人怎么说他们的
Oh, you know what they say about them.
艾迪 你要让他改一改
Eddie, you want to beat that out of him.
我就是那么做的
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
我去开门
I'll get it.
在十分钟内会第一次出现
...will first appear in about 10 minutes’ time
坐在国家金色马车里
riding in the gold coach of state.
汤米 告诉我
Tommy, talk to me.
我要搞清楚你家到底发生了什么
I need to know exactly what happened inside your house.
你到底知道不知道你在做什么
What the blazes do you think you're doing?
我想要帮忙 爸爸
I wanna help, Dad!
康诺利先生
Mr Connolly.
住口 你
Shut your face, you.
不管你是谁
Whoever you are.
我们自己能处理这事
We can handle this ourselves!
听着 你这小废物
Listen, you little twerp.
你小子牙都还没长齐
You're hardly out of the blooming cradle
所以我不期望你明白
so I don't expect you to understand,
但我有立场要去维护
but I've got a position to maintain.
这里的人尊敬我
People round here respect me.
这关系到别人怎么想
It matters what people think.
这就是你这样做的原因吗 爸
Is that why you did it, Dad?
你什么意思 做了什么
What do you mean? Did what?
你举报了外婆
You ratted on Gran.
警察怎么会知道该搜查那里
How else would the police know where to look?
除非某个胆小鬼向他们告密了
Unless some coward told them.
你胆敢
How dare you?
你以为我参加战争
You think I fought a war
就是为了让你这样多嘴的小废物叫我胆小鬼吗
just so a mouthy little scum like you could call me a coward!
你不明白 是吧
You don't get it, do you?
你和法西斯战斗过 记得吗
You fought against fascism, remember?
别人告诉你如何生活
People telling you how to live.
能和谁成为朋友 能和谁恋爱
Who you could be friends with. Who you could fall in love with.
谁能生存 谁必须死
Who could live and who had to die.
你还不明白吗
Don't you get it?
你们战斗 所以像我这样的废物
You were fighting so that little twerps like me
能做我们想做的 说我们想说的
could do what we want, say what we want.
现在你却变得和他们一样
Now you've become just like them.
是你举报了每个人 对吧
You've been informing on everyone, haven't you?
甚至是外婆
Even Gran.
就是为了保护你宝贵的声誉
All to protect your precious reputation!
艾迪
Eddie,
这是真的吗
is that true?
瑞塔 这是为了我们好
I did it for us, Rita.
她是丑恶的
She was filthy!
丑恶 令人厌恶的怪物
A filthy disgusting thing!
她是我母亲
She's my mother.
你举报的其他所有人 我们街区的那些人
All the others you informed on, all the people in our street,
我们的朋友
our friends.
我不得不这样做
I had to.
我只是在做该做的事
I did the right thing.
到底是为我们好
The right thing for us
还是为你自己 艾迪
or for you, Eddie?
你去吧 汤米
You go, Tommy.
和医生一起做些好事
Go with the Doctor and do some good.
离开这房子 这是毒药
Get away from this house. It's poison.
我们家里出了个红魔鬼
We've had a ruddy monster under our roof all right,
但不是我母亲
but it weren't my mother!
瑞塔
Rita!
汤米
Tommy.
那是怎么回事
What was all that, then?
那是…那是某件事情结束的声音
That was... That was the sound of something ending.
也是时候了 大家都还好吗
And about time, too. Everyone all right?
真不错
Smashing.
没什么东西能破坏我们的大日子
Nothing's gonna spoil our big day, is it?
汤米 告诉我那一晚的事
Tommy, tell me about that night,
她改变的那一晚
the night she changed.
她只是在看电视
She was just watching the telly.
洛斯说过
Rose said it.
她直接猜中了
She guessed it straightaway.
当然了 小街上的这些天线 怎么来的
Of course she did. All these aerials in one little street. How come?
街头的麦吉派先生卖得很便宜
Bloke up the road, Mr Magpie, he's selling them cheap.
现在呢
Is he, now?
快来
Come on!
你不能这么做…
You can't do that.
买东西
Shop!
如果你在 出来和我谈谈
If you're here, come out and talk to me,
麦吉派
Magpie!
或许他出去了
Maybe he's out.
看上去是的
Looks like it.
你好
Oh, hello.
这不对劲 非常不对劲
This isn't right. This is very much not right.
尝起来像铁 电木
Tastes like iron. Bakelite.
人工组装 做工粗糙 对了
Knocked together with human hands, yes,
但这设计本身
but the design itself...
噢 干的漂亮 真简单
Oh, beautiful work. That is so simple.
真不可思议 它像一台电视 但可携带
That's incredible. It's like a television, but portable.
一台便携式电视机
A portable television!
这不是这房间唯一的能量源
It's not the only power source in this room.
外婆
TOMMY: Gran.
我来了
I'm on my way.
你们在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我要我朋友复原
I want my friend restored
我想这超出了一个小小的后街电工的能力
and I think that's beyond a little backstreet electrician,
告诉我 谁在主管
so tell me, who's really in charge here?
哟呵 我想你在说我
Yoo-hoo! I think that must be me.
噢
Oh,
这个人聪明极了
this one's smart as paint.
她在和我们说话吗
Is she talking to us?
抱歉了 先生们 恐怕这是你们自找的
I'm sorry, gentlemen, I'm afraid you've brought this on yourselves.
我向你们介绍我的新…
May I introduce you to my new
朋友
friend.
很高兴见到你们
Jolly nice to meet you.
我的天哪 是她
Oh, my God, it's her.
那个电视上的女人
That woman off the telly!
不 它只是借用了的她的影像
No. It's just using her image. What?
什么
What?
你是什么
What are you?
我是电线人
I'm The Wire.
我要把你吃掉 帅小伙
And I will gobble you up, pretty boy.
一口一口的吃
Every last morsel!
当我饱餐之后
And when I have feasted,
我就能恢复物质形态
I shall regain the corporeal body,
我的同类阻止我这样做
which my fellow kind denied me.
天哪 彩色电视
Good Lord. Colour television.
所以你的同类试图阻止你
So your own people tried to stop you?
他们处死了我
They executed me,
但我用这种形式逃脱了
but l escaped in this form
然后飞越星际
and ﬂed across the stars.
现在 你困在了电视里
And now you're trapped in the television.
不会很久
Not for much longer.
医生 就是它抢走了我的外婆
Doctor, is this what got my gran?
是的 汤米
Yes, Tommy.
它靠脑电波为生
It feeds off the electrical activity of the brain,
但它把自己喂得像一只肥猪
but it gorges itself like a great, over-fed pig.
贪得无厌的夺走人们的脸
Taking people's faces, their essence as it stuffs itself.
是你纵容她那么做的 麦吉派
And you let her do it, Magpie.
我不得不这么做
I had to.
她答应放过我的脸
She allowed me my face.
她答应会在示威时间释放我
She's promised to release me at the time of manifestation.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
上任时间
The appointed time.
我至高无上的荣耀
My crowning glory
博士 加冕典礼
Doctor, the Coronation!
这是历史上第一次 有百万人聚集在电视机前
For the first time in history, millions gathered round a television set.
但你还不够强大 是吧
But you're not strong enough yet, are you?
你无法在这里动手
You can't do it all from here.
这就是为什么你需要这个
That's why you need this.
它需要更强大的东西
You need something more powerful.
这个能把一个巨大的发射器转换成接收器
This will turn a big transmitter into a big receiver.
你真是个聪明的家伙
What a clever thing you are.
但为什么要为此担忧呢
But why fret about it?
不如放松一下
Why not just relax?
踢开鞋子 尽情享受加冕礼
Kick off your shoes and enjoy the Coronation.
相信我
Believe me,
你会粘在屏幕上的
you'll be glued to the screen.
医生 等一下
Doctor! Hold on.
饿 饿
Hungry! Hungry!
电线人很饿
The Wire is hungry!
这个很美味
Oh, this one is tasty!
我能吃下很多个他
Oh, I'll have lashings of him.
美味
Delicious!
武器
Armed?
他有武器 又很聪明
He's armed and clever.
撤退 撤退
Withdraw! Withdraw!
那个盒子 麦吉派
The box, Magpie,
那个盒子
the box!
抓紧了
Hold tight!
引导我到达胜利 麦吉派
Conduct me to my victory, Magpie.
饿 饿
Hungry! Hungry
喂饱我
Feed me!
噢 她好可爱
Oh, she's so lovely!
漂亮
RITA: Beautiful.
让人忘掉所有烦恼
Makes you forget all your troubles.
大家准备好放礼炮
Everyone all right for pop?
汤米 醒醒
Tommy, wake up!
汤米 快来
Tommy, come on!
怎么回事
What happened?
麦吉派去哪了?
Where's Magpie?
我们甚至不知到从哪里找起 太迟了
We don't even know where to start looking. It's too late.
永远不会太迟 一个智者说过
Never too late, as a wise person once said.
我想是凯莉吧
Kylie, I think.
电线人有个大计划 它需要…
The Wire's got big plans. It'll need...
它想要吸收一半的人口
She's gonna harvest half the population.
数百万的人 我们在哪
Millions and millions of people. And where are we?
马斯韦尔山
Muswell Hill.
马斯韦尔山 也就是说…
Muswell Hill! Which means...
亚历山德拉宫殿
Alexandra Palace!
伦敦北部最大的电视发射器
Biggest TV transmitter in North London. Oh!
这就是为什么它选中这个地方 汤米
What's why it chose this place, Tommy!
你要做什么
What are you gonna do?
我要去购物
I'm going shopping.
你要找这个吗
Is this what you want?
太好了 好的
Perfect! Right,
我还需要一样东西
I need one more thing.
好了 走吧
Got it. Let's go.
我做不到
I can't do this!
求你 请不要逼迫我
Please! Please, don't make me.
时间即将到来
The time is at hand.
喂饱我
Feed me!
那里
There!
快来
Come on!
等等 你们想干什么…
Wait, wait, wait. Where do we think we...
很抱歉 阁下
Oh, I'm very sorry, sir.
你不应该在加冕仪式上吗
Shouldn't you be at the Coronation?
他们给我留了个座位
They' re saving me a seat.
他认为你是谁
Who'd he think you were?
比利时国王
King of Belgium apparently.
把这个接通
Keep this switched on.
不让任何人阻止你 汤米
Don't let anyone stop you, Tommy.
一切都依靠它了 明白吗
Everything depends on it, you understand?
去那儿你会丧命的
You'll get yourself killed up there!
陛下
Your Majesty!
喂饱我
Feed me!
盛宴
Ah! Feast!
饱餐
Feasting!
电线人正在饱餐
The Wire is feasting!
太晚了
It's too late.
对我们所有人都太晚了
It's too late for all of us!
我要吃掉你 博士
I shall consume you, Doctor!
我不能让你这么做 麦吉派
I won't let you do this, Magpie!
帮帮我 博士
Help me, Doctor!
好痛
It burns!
它带走了我的脸
It took my face,
我的灵魂
"My soul!
你不能阻止电线人
You cannot stop The Wire.
很快 我就能向你证明
Soon, I shall become manifest.
不 不要再这样
No more. No more of this.
你答应给我安宁
You promised me peace.
那我就给你安宁
Then peace you shall have.
一根蜡烛的两端同时燃烧
Been burning the candle at both ends?
你过度扩展自己了 女士
You've over-extended yourself, missus.
你不应该让可怜的老麦吉派消失的
You shouldn't have had a crack at poor old Magpie there.
橡胶鞋底 可靠极了
Rubber soles, swear by them.
亲爱的
Oh, dear.
你的小计划哪里出错了 博士
Has our little plan gone horribly wrong, Doctor?
不
No!
现在结束了 收场白都没有
It's closed down, I'm afraid, and no epilogue.
我错过了什么
What have I missed?
博士 发生什么了
Doctor! What happened?
解决了 电能生物 电视技术
Sorted. Electrical creature. TV technology.
聪明的外星人
Clever alien life form.
顺便说一下 那是我
That's me, by the way.
我把接收器切换回发射器
I turned the receiver back into a transmitter
然后把电线人困在这里面了
and I trapped The Wire in here.
我刚刚提前三十年发明了家庭录像机
I just invented the home video 30 years early.
大尺寸录像系统
Betamax.
噢 看啊
Oh, look!
天佑女王 是吧
God save the Queen, eh?
这不是你的房子
This was never your house.
是我母亲名下的
It's in my mother's name.
代表她 我告诉你…
And on her behalf, I'm telling you,
滚
out.
我们可以去购物广场 加入人群
We could go down the Mall, join in with the crowds.
不 那只是排场
No, that's just pomp and circumstance.
这里才是历史
This is history, right here.
接地气
The domestic approach?
的确
DOCTOR: Exactly.
它…那东西…它永远困在录像机里了吗
Will it... That thing... is it trapped for good on the video?
希望如此 但是为了保险起见
Hope so. just to be on the safe side, though,
我会使用我高超的跨时间消除法知识
I'll use my unrivalled knowledge of trans-temporal extirpation methods
去中和残余的电子排布
to neutralise the residual electronic pattern.
你的什么
You what?
我一遍一遍录制它
I'm going to tape over it.
这个交给我 我经常这么做
just leave it to me. I'm always doing that.
汤米 那辆小摩托归你了 小小礼物
Tell you what, Tommy. You can have the scooter. Little present.
但最好在车库里放它几年
Best keep it in the garage for a few years.
总算摆脱他了
Good riddance.
就这样吧 汤米
Is that it, then, Tommy?
新君主 新时代 新世界
New monarch, new age, new world.
没有艾迪·康诺利这样的人的容身之处
No room for a man like Eddie Connolly. That's right.
对 他自作自受
Right. He deserves it.
汤米 去追他
Tommy, go after him.
为什么
What for?
他是你爸爸
He's your dad.
他是个白痴
He's an idiot.
他当然是 但是如我说的 他是你爸
Course he is. Like I said, he's your dad.
你很聪明
But you're clever,
聪明到能够拯救世界 所以别停滞于此
clever enough to save the world so don't stop there.
去吧
Go on.
这里已经超出了塔迪斯的知识范围
We've gone beyond the reach of the Tardis' knowledge.
这可不是好事
Not a good move.
这文字很古老了
This writing is old.
难以置信的古老
Impossibly old.
是人 看看 真的是人
People! Look at that, real people.
是我们 万岁
That's us. Hooray!
野兽及他的大军要从深渊中崛起
The Beast and his armies shall rise from the pit...
不管下面那是什么 绝不是自然现象
Whatever it is down there, it's not a natural phenomenon.
我们可以改革现代科学
We could revolutionise modern science.
我们可以利用它加速帝国发展
We could use it to fuel the empire.
或者发起一场战争
Or start a war.
这是黑洞
That's a black hole.
但这不可能
But that's impossible.